慢点
Not so fast.
你不想去那里
You didn't want to be there.
所以我才会试图跟你交谈
That's why I tried to talk to you.
格伦告诉我  你救了他的命
Glenn told me you saved his life.
他救了我的命
He saved mine.
我们就该这样互相照顾  对吗
That's how it works with us, right?
对
Right.
去找点吃的
Get something to eat.
日出时我们动身
We'll start back at sunup.
跟瑞克谈了谈
Talked to Rick.
有些人知道你在监狱
Some of them know what you did
做的事
at the prison.
达里尔  玛姬
Daryl, Maggie.
他们接受了
They accept it.
如果他们没接受  你不会在这里
You wouldn't be here if they didn't.
我要跟其余人聊聊
Gonna talk to the rest of them.
让他们也接受
Tell them to accept it, too.
他们没必要接受
They don't have to.
不  有必要
No, they do.
真的有必要
They just do.
我们没必要告诉他们小女孩的事
We don't need to tell them about the girls.
我不想说
I don't want to.
为什么
Why?
我得忘记那事
I just need to forget it.
我来
I got it.
那就是我们等待时机的原因
Right there is why we're waiting for our moment.
好吧  有道理
Yeah, fair enough.
感谢你救我一命
I owe you everything.
你应该感谢泰尔西  他当时在监狱
You owe Tyreese. He was at the prison.
你回去了
You got back there.
这在他们的一间储藏室里
It was in one of their storerooms.
我看见他们杀了他
I saw them kill him.
那孩子
That kid.
我还是不知道你做了什么
I still don't know about what you did...
但我知道  你懂一些我不懂的事
But I know you knew some things I didn't.
我让你独自前行
I sent you away to this--
你说过我能活下来  你说得对
You said I could survive. You were right.
我让你独自前行  现在我们加入了你
I sent you away to this and now we're joining you.
你愿意接纳我们吗
Will you have us?
谢谢
Thank you.
我不想谈论这事
I don't want to talk about it.
我做不到
I can't.
我得忘记这事
I just need to forget it.
好吧
All right.
没事
It's nothing.
我们投降
We surrender.
没踪迹  什么也没有
No tracks. No nothing.
所以不管你昨晚听到了什么...
So whatever you heard last night...
我有不祥的预感
It's more what I felt.
如果有人在监视我们
If someone was watching us,
应该会发生一些事才对
there would have been something.
跟紧点
Keep close.
准备好踏上水泥地了吗
Ready to get some concrete under your feet?
是时候了
I think it's time.
真是悦耳啊  警官
That is sweet music to my ears, officer.
再遇到一条路我们就沿路走
Take the next road we come to,
继续朝北走直到发现车辆
try to get back to going north till we find a vehicle.
-好吗  -好
- Good? - Good.
跟紧点
Tighten it up.
湿袜子
Uh, wet socks.
脚凉快
Cool feet.
蚊子咬
Mosquito bites.
瘙痒让你知道自己还活着
Itching reminds you you're alive.
处处都有危险
Danger around every corner.
一刻也不无聊
Never a dull moment.
日头毒辣
The hot sun beating down on you.
晒成漂亮的棕色
Come on, a glorious tan.
我说的是真心话
I said it and I meant it.
没有隐私
No privacy.
有忠实的观众
Captive audience.
再来一个
One more.
他对那个可真是拿手
He's a damn expert at that.
-什么啊  -一个小游戏
- What was it? - A little game.
坏事里头找好事
Good out of the bad.
救命
Help!
-救命  来人啊  救命  -爸爸  快
- Help, anybody! Help! - Dad, come on.
快啊
Come on!
-快啊  -来人啊  救救我
- Come on. - Anyone, help!
救命
Help!
救命  救命  救命
Help! Help! Help!
来人啊  救命
Anybody, help!
救命啊
Help!
救救我
救命  救命
Help! Help!
救命啊  救命啊
安全了  注意观察
We're clear. Keep watch.
下来吧
Come on down.
你没事吧
You okay?
对不起
Sorry.
是的
Yes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我叫加百利
I'm Gabriel.
你身上有武器吗
Do you have any weapons on you?
我看起来像是会有武器的人吗
Do I look like I would have any weapons?
我们才不管你看起来像不像
We don't give two short and curlies what it looks like.
我没有任何武器
I have no weapons of any kind.
上帝之道足以庇护我
The word of god is the only protection I need.
看上去可不像这样
Sure didn't look like it.
我向天呼救  救援就来了
I called for help. Help came.
你们有
Do you have--
有吃的吗
Have any food?
我之前
Whatever I--
剩下的食物  都已经掉了
I had left, it just hit the ground.
这里有核桃
We've got some pecans.
谢谢
Thank you.
真是个美丽的孩子
That's a beautiful child.
-你们有营地吗  -没有  你呢
- Do you have a camp? - No. Do you?
我有个教堂
I have a church.
把手举过头顶
Hold your hands above your head.
你杀过多少行尸
How many walkers have you killed?
-一只也没  -转过去
- Not any, actually. - Turn around.
你杀过多少人
How many people have you killed?
没杀过
None.
为什么
Why?
因为上帝憎恶暴力
Because the lord abhors violence.
你都做过什么
What have you done?
我们都做过肮脏的事
We've all done something.
我是个罪人
I'm a sinner.
我几乎每天都犯下罪行
I sin almost every day.
但我只向上帝忏悔那些罪行
But those sins, I confess them to god,
而不是向陌生人
Not strangers.
你说你有个教堂
You said you had a church?
喂  之前
Hey, earlier,
是你在监视我们吗
Were you watching us?
我只管自己的事
I keep to myself.
这年头  活人和死人
Nowadays, people are just as dangerous
一样危险  你们觉得呢
As the dead, don't you think?
不  人更危险
No, people are worse.
总之我没有监视你们
Well, I wasn't watching you.
灾变后  我最远只去过几次
I haven't been beyond the stream near my church
教堂边上的河流
More than a few times since it all started.
今天之前  我最远只到过那儿
That was the furthest I've gone before today.
或许我在说谎
Or maybe I'm lying.
也许我全是骗你们的
Maybe I'm lying about everything
前面根本没有什么教堂
and there's no church ahead at all.
也许我在把你们带向陷阱
Maybe I'm leading you into a trap
以偷走你们的松鼠
so I can steal all your squirrels.
教区的教徒们常说
Members of my flock had often told me
我的幽默感令人扶额
that my sense of humor leaves much to be desired.
的确如此
Yeah, it does.
圣莎拉教堂
等等
Hold up.
可以让我们先检查一下吗
Can we take a look around first?
我们可不想把松鼠拱手送人
We just want to hold on to our squirrels.
神赐恩宠
汝不可杀人
创世纪
我们行善  不可丧志  若不灰心  到了时候就要收成
加拉太书  6:9
迷途40年
我在这儿待了好几个月  连大门都没出
I spent months here without stepping out the front door.
如果你们发现里面有人
If you found someone inside,
那可就奇了怪了
Well, it would have been surprising.
谢了
Thanks for this.
我们在后院发现一辆小巴士
We found a short bus out back.
但无法发动
It don't run,
不过我敢说一两天就能修好
but I bet we could fix that in less than a day or two.
神父说他不要那辆车
Father here says he doesn't want it.
看来我们有交通工具了
Looks like we found ourselves some transport.
你清楚现在的当务之急  对吧
You understand what's at stake here, right?
我清楚
Yes, I do.
既然现在可以休息...
Now that we can take a breath--
休息就要拖慢进度
We take a breath, we slow down,
拖慢了就要出岔子
Shit inevitably goes down.
不管接下来要干嘛  我们都需要补给
We need supplies no matter what we do next.
说得没错
That's right.
水  食物  弹药
Water, food, ammunition.
别开那辆车
Short bus ain't going nowhere.
我去给你们找些焗豆
Bring you back some baked beans.
无论如何都要跟瑞克步调一致
One way or another, we're doing what Rick does.
大伙儿别再走散了
We're not splitting up again.
我听他的
What he said.
我们很想跟你们走  但还是听她的吧
We want to roll with you, but... What she said.
你靠什么活了这么久
How'd you survive here for so long?
补给从哪儿来的
Where did your supplies come from?
靠运气
Luck.
年度罐装食物捐赠活动
Our annual canned food drive.
刚刚举行完就出事了
Things fell apart right after we finished it.
只剩我一个人
It was just me.
过来  朱迪思
Come here, judith.
我靠那些食物撑了很久
The food lasted a long time.
后来我便四处搜索补给
And then I started scavenging.
把附近的房子都清了一遍
I've cleaned out every place nearby.
除了一个地方
Except for one.
你为什么不去那儿
What kept you from it?
被行尸占据了
It's overrun.
有多少
How many?
十多只吧  或许更多
A dozen or so. Maybe more.
我们能拿下十多只
We can handle a dozen.
我和鲍勃跟你去
Bob and I will go with you.
泰尔西留下
Tyreese should stay here,
保护朱迪思
help keep judith safe.
可以吗
That'll be okay?
当然
Sure.
假如你需要我照看她
You ever need me to watch her,
或者需要我为她做任何事  我都愿意
need anything for her, I'm right here.
非常感谢
I'm grateful for it.
还有谢谢你做的其它一切
And everything else.
-我给你们画张地图  -没必要
- I'll draw you a map. - You don't need to.
你和我们一起去
You're coming with us.
我什么忙也帮不上
I'm not gonna be of any help.
你们也看见了
You saw me.
我不会对付行尸
I'm no good around those things.
你和我们一起去
You're coming with us.
听着
Listen,
-我不信任这个人  -为什么
- I don't trust this guy.  - Why?
你为什么信任他
Why do you trust him?
并非所有人都是坏人
Everybody can't be bad.
我不信任这个人
I don't trust this guy.
所以我要带上他
And that's why I'm bringing him with me.
但他可能有其他同伴
But he could have friends.
所以我需要你时刻警惕
So I need you to stay alert
帮着泰尔西保护朱迪思  好吗
and help Tyreese protect Judith, okay?
现在
Now...
我要你听好了我接下来要说的话
I need you to hear what I'm about to say.
好的
Okay.
你并不安全
You are not safe.
无论你身边有多少人
No matter how many people are around
无论这里看起来有多安全
or how clear the area looks,
无论其他人怎么说
no matter what anyone says,
无论你自己怎么想
no matter what you think,
你并不安全
you are not safe.
只要一秒钟
It only takes one second.
就一秒  然后就结束了
One second and it's over.
永远不要放松警惕  永远不要
Never let your guard down, ever.
我要你向我保证
I want you to promise me.
-我保证  -好的
- I promise. - Okay.
爸爸
Dad.
你说得没错  我是很强大
You're right. I am strong.
我们俩都很强大
We both are.
但是我们足够强大
But we're strong enough
依然可以帮助别人
that we can still help people.
如果有不测  我们也能照顾好自己
And we can handle ourselves if things go wrong.
我们足够强大
And we're strong enough
无需害怕
that we don't have to be afraid
也没必要躲躲藏藏
and we don't have to hide.
他有所隐瞒
Well, he's hiding something.
我会保护好自己的  爸爸
I'll stay safe, dad.
好的
Yeah.
你说过他们没资格活下去
When you said they don't get to live,
你没说错
you weren't wrong.
我们冲破自己的底线  放弃一些东西
We push ourselves and let things go.
然后越放弃越多
Then we let some more go and some more.
很快  很多事情就无法挽回了
And pretty soon, there's things we can't get back.
有些原则就算我们很努力也无法坚守了
Things we couldn't hold on to even if we tried.
我们要去华盛顿  瑞克
Washington's gonna happen, Rick.
我还没决定我们要不要去
I haven't decided if we're going.
是的  我知道  没关系
Yeah, I know, and that's cool.
但你也看到亚伯拉罕的作战实力了
But you've seen Abraham in action.
他会去那  尤金会阻止灾变
He's gonna get there and Eugene's gonna cure all this
很快你就会发现
and you're gonna find yourself
生活又恢复原状了
in a place where it's like how it used to be.
如果你变得过于麻木
And if you've let too much go along the way,
就没办法恢复了
that's not gonna work.
因为你会回到现实生活中
'Cause you gonna be back in the real world.
这才是现实生活  鲍勃
This is the real world, Bob.
才不是
Naw.
这是一场噩梦  迟早会醒来
This is a nightmare, and nightmares end.
对不起  我要决定了
I'm sorry. I'm calling it.
我们要去华盛顿  你要答应
Washington's gonna happen. You're gonna say yes.
呼声已经很高了
Already too much momentum.
你不能跟市政府对着干
You can't fight city hall.
或许这一点是我们不能放弃的
Maybe that's just one of those parts of not letting go.
我懂
Hey, I get it.
你不想谈
You don't want to talk about it.
你没事吧
You okay?
我必须没事
Gotta be.
我们要重新开始
We get to start over.
大家一起重新来过
All of us with each other.
你一个人救了我们大家
You saved us all by yourself.
只是运气罢了
We got lucky.
要不然我们早就死了
We all should be dead.
我去看看
I'll check it.
好的
All right.
我们没有死
We ain't dead.
已经发生的事无法改变
And whatever happened, happened.
我们重新开始吧
Let's start over.
-我想重新开始  -你可以
- I want to. - Well, you can.
我们把东西留在这里
We should leave this here for backup
如果在教堂里出什么事的话好有个后路
in case things go south at the church.
需要我帮你拿一个吗
Want me to carry one of those?
不用
No.
当我们在电话簿里
You know, I didn't want to mention anything
找这个地方的时候  我不想说什么  但是
when we looked this place up in the phone book, but...
我只是觉得如今枪支店不可能还剩东西
I just can't imagine a gun store having leftovers nowadays.
看上去情况不妙  是吧
Don't look good, does it?
是行尸吗
Was it a walker?
是的  是行尸
Uh, yeah. It was a walker.
真的吗
Really?
其实是一堆箱子和一个拖把把我绊倒了
It was a stack of boxes and a mop and I tripped.
但是
Still...
我拿到了我们需要的东西
Got what we came for.
你还真找到东西了吗
You actually found something?
小冰箱里藏了三个消声器
Three silencers stashed in a mini-fridge.
找东西的第一条规则
Rule number one of scavenging--
这世界上尚存的所有东西都是藏起来的
There's nothing left in this world that isn't hidden.
到了
We're here.
这里曾是慈善食品银行
This was the Food Bank.
家庭所需  食物银行  旧货商店  捐赠请往里走
曾经服务了整个郡
It served the whole county.
我教堂里的所有罐头都会送到这里来
All the cans at my church were gonna end up here.
如果下水道会吐
If a sewer could puke,
闻起来肯定是这样的
this is what it'd smell like.
屋顶漏水已经有一段时间了
The water's been coming down that hole for a while.
让这里满是污水
Slimed this place up good.
我们可以用架子挡住它们
We can use the shelves to block them.
就这样  萨沙
Yeah, that's it, Sasha.
就这么办
There's our way.
把架子弄下去
Down those shelves.
我说过  你要跟紧我们
I said you're coming with us.
快  快
Go! Go!
它们来了
Here they come.
你负责右边
You take right.
这边我看到三只
I see three here.
你准备了吗
You got it?
我们得去救加百利
We have to get Gabriel.
怎么回事
What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
好
All right,
我们推倒这个架子  砸向前面这几只行尸
we'll push down the shelves on the ones in front of us.
我们杀过去  然后我去救他
We'll fight through and I'll grab him.
开始
Go!
是啊
Yeah.
我知道它们要从哪条路过来
I know which way it's gonna break.
鲍勃
Bob!
你还好吗  鲍勃  你还好吗
You okay? Bob, you okay?
我现在没事了[双关]
I'm fine now.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我  我慌了
I-- I panicked.
我告诉过你  我...
I told you I...
她活着时是你的熟人吗
You knew her when she was alive?
我明白了
Yeah, I get it.
你只对上帝坦白罪孽
You only tell your sins to God.
你想念你的刀吗
Do you miss the sword?
本来也不是我的
Wasn't really mine in the first place.
灾变刚开始时找来的
Found it, in the very beginning.
你身手为何这么好
How'd you get so good?
在外面除了我就是它们
It was just me and them out here
日复一日
all day, every day.
像这样过了很久
A good long time.
我不知道那是什么  但那不是生活
I don't know what that was, but it wasn't a life.
不像今天
Not like today.
在三尺深的污水中举步维艰地寻找食物
Stumbling around in three feet of slime for some peas and carrots,
这才叫生活
that's living.
我想安德莉亚了
I miss Andrea.
我也想赫谢尔
I miss Hershel.
我不怀念在这之前的生活
I don't miss what was before.
我不想那把刀
I don't miss that sword.
泰尔西说你在后面
Tyreese said you were out back.
进来吧  我们找到食物了
Come on in. We found food.
-有不少呢  -很好
- A lot of it. - Good.
这是什么
What is it?
这些划痕
Those scratches.
深深地刻在窗框上
They're deep.
好像是有人用刀子划的
Like knives or something.
有人想进去
Someone was trying to get in.
我还找到了一些东西
I found something else.
我不确定到底发生了什么  但无论什么事
I don't know what happened, but whatever it is,
我们都可以解决
we can handle it.
虽然这不意味着加百利是坏人
Doesn't mean Gabriel is a bad guy for sure,
但它一定意味着什么
but it means something.
你会因此下地狱
我想祝酒
I'd like to propose a toast.
我环顾这个房间
I look around this room...
我看到了生存者
And I see survivors.
在座的每一位
Each and every one of you
都赢得了这个称号
has earned that title.
-敬生存者  -生存者  干杯
- To the survivors. - Survivors! Cheers!
干杯
Cheers.
生存者
Survivors.
你们只想当生存者吗
Is that all you want to be?
早上醒来
Wake up in the morning,
与行尸搏斗  四处觅食
fight the undead pricks, forage for food,
夜晚也无法安心入睡
go to sleep at night with two eyes open,
就这样周而复始
rinse and repeat?
你们可以这样做
'cause you can do that.
因为你们有实力
I mean, you got the strength.
你们也有技能
You got the skill.
问题是  对于你们来说
Thing is, for you people,
对于你们的能力而言  那只意味着屈服
for what you can do, that's just surrender.
我们把尤金送到华盛顿  他将消灭行尸
Now, we get Eugene to Washington and he will make the dead die
让活人重新掌控世界
and the living will have this world again.
虽然路途艰辛 但值得一搏
And that is not a bad takeaway for a little road trip.
尤金  特区有什么
Eugene, what's in DC?
他们建了个基地  足以应对
Infrastructure constructed to withstand pandemics
时下的瘟疫狂潮
even of this fubar magnitude.
那里有食物  燃料和避难所
That means food, fuel, refuge.
一切重新开始
Restart.
无论结果怎么样
However this plays out,
无论花多长时间才能重新开始
however long it takes for the reset button to kick in,
你们在那里都会更安全
you can be safe there.
比灾变后的任一时期都安全
Safer than you've been since this whole thing started.
跟我们走吧
Come with us.
为小家伙拯救世界
Save the world for that little one.
为你们自己拯救世界
Save it for yourselves.
为那些在外逃难
Save it for the people out there...
除了生存别无希望的人拯救世界
who don't got nothing left to do except survive.
怎么了
What was that?
我想她知道我要说什么
I think she knows what I'm about to say.
她要加入  她加入我就加入
She's in. If she's in, I'm in.
-我们加入  -太好了
- We're in. -Yeah.
来吧
Let's do it.
好
Okay.
我不会让我哥哥
I'm not letting my brother
独享抱那孩子的乐趣
be the only one that gets to hold that baby.
等等
Wait.
再来一个
One more.
-你还好吗  -挺好的
- You okay? - Yeah, yeah.
我去过监狱
I was at the prison.
跟总督一起
With the Governor.
我那时不知道他是谁
I didn't know who he was
他会做什么
or what he could do.
也不了解你们
And I didn't know who all of you were.
我只是不想隐瞒
I-- I just didn't want it to be hidden.
我在那里待过
That I was there.
你现在跟我们在一起
You're here with us now.
感谢招待
Thanks for the hospitality.
你竟然肯让我们喝你的圣餐酒让我很意外
I'm surprised you let us drink your communion wine.
没有人吃圣餐了
There isn't anyone left to take communion.
没祝福过的酒只是普通的酒罢了
The wine's just wine until it's blessed.
你一定隐瞒了什么
You're hiding something.
而且很显然是你无法逃避的事
And it's pretty obvious it's something you can't hide from.
那是你的事
That's your business.
但是这些人
But these people,
这些人是我的家人
these people are my family.
如果你隐瞒的事情会伤害到他们
And if what you're hiding somehow hurts them in any way,
我会杀了你
I'll kill you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
不知道
I don't know.
快来
Come on.
你在干什么  你在干什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
贝丝在他们手上
They got Beth.
快点  上车
Come on. Come on, get in.
你醒了吗
You waking up?
你醒来了
Ah, you're back with us, huh?
好消息是
Good news is...
你还没死
You're not dead yet.
松了一口气  对吗
That's a relief, right?
但别高兴的太早
But try not to read too much into the word yet there.
否则你会疯掉的  鲍勃
It'll just drive you crazy, Bob.
我想解释一下自己
I want to explain myself a little.
你瞧
You see,
我们刚才并不想
We didn't want to hurt you...
伤害你
before.
我们不想让你脱离团队  或吓唬你
We didn't want to pull you away from your group or scare you.
我们不想这样做
These aren't things that we want to do.
我们只是必须这样做
They're things we got to do.
你和你的伙伴夺走了我们的家
You and your people took away our home.
这很正常
That's fair play.
现在我们像其他人一样
Now we're out here like everybody else
试图在外面生存
trying to survive.
为了生存
And in order to do that,
我们必须狩猎
We have to hunt.
最早的时候
Didn't start that way,
我们不吃人
eating people.
事情演化成了这样
It evolved into that.
我们进化了
We evolved.
我们不得不
We had to.
而现在  我们退化了
And now we've devolved
变成了猎人
into hunters.
我给你说过
I told you.
我说过回不去了  鲍勃
I said it. Can't go back, Bob.
我只是希望你明白
I just hope you understand
你身上发生的事不是私人恩怨
that nothing happening to you now is personal.
对  是你害我们落到这般境地
Yeah, you put us in this situation
而现在躺在这里的人是你
and it is almost kind of a cosmic justice
似乎是某种报应  但是
for it to be you, but...
换做别人我们也会这样做的
We would have done this to anybody.
我们会的
We will.
但是归根结底
But at the end of the day,
不管我们多么讨厌这种丑陋的事
No matter how much we hate all this ugly business...
人总是要吃东西的
A man's got to eat.
如果能让你感到安慰的话
If it makes you feel any better...
你的味道比我们想的好多了
You taste much better than we thought you would.